There is a brother there - tall; towards the end of this row,
Just raise up your hand.
Can I speak to you sir ?
Yes, sir
There is a charm you are carrying up and down.
Can you go get the charm ?
Yes. Sir.
Outside one of the entrances to the SCOAN
Narration in French
You are a witch doctor.
Yes.
People consult you.
Yes. Sir.
I am seeing this thing appears. A human being appears to you every night
Yes.
They surround you and they want to kill you.
Yes. Sir. They used to eat with me.
And at times my wife would ask, 'what is that ?' I would say nothing.
I used to prepare some charms for people.
If a costomer comes to me and asks me for something, I would ask them
for the kind of charm. They would then explain themselves.
The items here have something I normally serve.
And I would serve it to them.
They would go to the place, everything would be as required, as needed.
This charm needed blood from me but I said I did not have blood
to give it to him. I don't want to serve him anymore.
Listen to me and confirm my words. Not that your don't want to serve him anymore.
Human beings appeared to you and said they wanted to kill you.
If not that they came to you physically that they wanted to kill you. You would not come out.
Yes. Sir.
You know you used to shout in the night ? You cry out ?
Yes sir. Sometimes, if I was in bed. The man would come
In a white Mercedes-Benz, wearing dreadlocks. He would wake me up.
Ask me to sit down and that he wanted to eat.
He said he needed blood, meaning he wanted to kill me.
He said he needed blood. Yes.
Can you address the people of God about the failure of this business.
The need to Jesus as our Lord and Savior.
Please viewers, I beg you all, this way is not a real way.
Follow Jesus Christ as the ultimate.
You became a preacher now !
No, no sir
I want to advise all the men.... this is your wife ? Yes, Sir
Can you tell us how he behaves at night when these people come ?
Since I married my husband almost 17 years ago. I was 18 at the time.
He would carry a little stick with a hole in it. He would place it on the floor and serve it.
And name it Ogbu and serve it with the blood of a fowl killed for that purpose.
He would plead with the Ogbu to save all members of the family.
And that word always touches my heart because if I ask my husband to
Surrender his life to Christ. I would not know his reaction. So I always prayed everyday.
Sometimes, when the children and I were asleep, I would hear his voice anc would be shocked.
I would hear my husband's voice in the midnight...
Shouting.
He would shout and be discussing as if there were someone with him.
How many of them are always with you ?
They can be 5 or 6, and they would surround me.
They are spiritual people, not the real people. Sir.
I would wake up from my sleep around 2 or 3 am and ask my husband,
Who were those people your were discussing with ?
In the middle of the night.
He has different types of juju (charm).
In the house.
Yes. One is Ogbu. One is Iroko. There are different names.
So, I asked my husband, 'Who are you talking to ?'
He told me they were those charms (juju). They wanted to take his life.
Because they needed blood. I then told my husband that we should pray.
We should pray. And take these things to church.
My husband then said to me, if these things (items) were taken to church.
How would he make money to feed me and my children ?
Can you see the problem you have been in for long ?
You keep crying and praying and you have given your life to Jesus.
But your daily bread comes from charms.
Your children, yourself, everybody have been affected.
Now there was a marriage. A woman that came to you.
And demanded for a charm.
Because her husband married another wife.
She is light in complexion.
You gave her this charm, and the charm worked badly.
Yes.
It affected the man.
You are right. Sir.
I am just telling you one of the things he has done.
Just one of the thousands.
We have many questions to ask you !
Which we will leave it till next Sunday!
Ok, I will receive you as my guests.
Your family, your children, you go ahead and bring them for deliverance.
Your home too, we'll go there. Make sure we pack everything.
There is another charm in your house, in the form of white calabash.
Yes. That one. I am afraid to carry.
The real one that can draw the evil agents is the one in the white calabash.
Yes sir, you are right.
Without prophetic gift and you confront this person
He will fight you over.
What he put down is still a test.
If he realize that I could not probe the issue forward, he will fight back.
The real issue is at home.
He prepared that char for N400,000.
There's a pigeon that used to fly out and back.
Yes.
Can you bring these things out.
The man is asked to bring out what is in the plastic bag.
His wife confirmed that the husband has many charms, different ones, and shrine.
There is a particular one that he used to pray to, and he killed a fowl for the blood to sacrifice to
The wife advised the husband several times to give up the charm, he would not listen.
Return them back to the bag.
Watch your screen, the man is packing back his charms.
Following the prophecy on Sunday concerning his life,
Mr Segun Maku was given Anointing Water by Prophet T.B. Joshua
to go and bring the charm he had left at home.
Mr Maku together with a member of The Emmanuel TV team.
board the bus outside the SCOAN.
They are on their way to get the charm that Prophet T.B. Joshua prophesied about on Sunday.
They arrived outside the house of Mr Maku
Disembarking, they enter the house where the charm is kept.
You are inside my room.
My name is Segun Maku.
This Anointing water for salvation, healing and deliverance -
he said that I should go and spray it on the charm and then carry the charm.
The charm is inside my room there. I am afraid to go there.
Mr Maku leads the team into his bedroom.
The charm is inside the box there.
This charm is very powerful. It can kill somebody ; it can even kill me.
I put the TV on top so that if somebody comes to my house.
they will not see anything, it's only the TV that they will see.
Mr Segun Maku brings out the bottle of the anointing water
In the name of Jesus Christ, in the blood of Jesus Christ.
Mr Maku takes the Television off the box.
Again spraying the anointing water for salvation, healing, and deliverance.
He causiously opens the box.
The demon there is very powerful.
In the name of Jesus Christ, in the blood of Jesus Christ.
Inside the box, is the pigeon and the white pot
containing the powerful charm the man of God prophesied about during the Sunday Service.
In the name of Jesus Christ, in the blood of Jesus Christ.
After the anointing water once again.
Mr Maku reaches out his hand to take the pigeon and the white pot containing the powerful charm out of the box.
This is the pigeon the man of God was talking about.
And this is the white bowl the man of God was talking about.
This pigeon, if somebody sees it, they will think that it's an ordinary pigeon.
It's not a pigeon; it's a demon.
This soap - if somebody came to me that they want to harm a human being,
I have a special bucket here and a special sponge.
that I will bath with.
This is the bucket, and this is the sponge.
I use it with that charm that will disfigure a human being's life.
I will tell the person to write the name of the person and
what he wants me to do to the person.
After writing it, I will use the soap to bathe.
After using it to bathe, the paper that he wrote his request on,
I will put it in the claws or the mouth of the pigeon and it will fly
and land on the roof of the person's house.
The next day, that evil will happen to the person.
The pigeon will come back to me; even if I am not around, it will wait for me.
If somebody sees the pigeon, they will think that it's an ordinary pigeon.
They won't know that it's a demon.
I can use it any way I want.
If it is blindness that he requests for the person.
The reason I was able to carry the pigeon and the bowl like this
is because of the Anointing Water. It gave me the power to carry it.
If not for the Anointing Water, I wouldn't be able to go near it
because it usually appears to me physically like a human being.
It wants to take my life but I don't want to die.
My father taught me all these things.
That was the work my father was doing before he handed it over to me.
I have to bathe before I even touch the charm,
before I use it to perform anything.
This thing is very powerful.
I can even send this bird to London - it will go and come back.
I get paid N400,000 to prepare this charm.
And now, the charm wants to kill me.
It used to appear to me face to face that it needs blood.
Sometimes, it will come with 6 members in a white vehicle, Mercedes-Benz;
they will come and request that they need blood.
If not for the Anointing Water, I would not even be able to touh or...
hold it like this.
Mr Maku begins to pack the bucket and sponge that he used to use.
together with the charm to take them to the SCOAN.
This demon - it's over three years, since it's been on top of that table there.
Mr Segun Maku once sprays the Anointing Water over the cardboard box containing the charm and pigeon.
He then carrys it out of his house.
And boards the vehicle waiting to take him to SCOAN.
Mr Segun Maku arrives safely to the SCOAN.
And make his way inside the church walkway.
Here is the man, the wife, and his children.
Man of God the charms are outside there,
I went home and brought them.
Mr Segun Maku said that he kept the charms outside the church auditorium.
Now that he moves to got and get them.
Going outside the church, we can see him at the back of a car,
When he brings out the carrier bag, and 2 cardboard boxes.
which contain the charms and diabolic items of his witch doctor's trait
Mr Segun Maku carries the boxes and the carrier bag containing all his charms
back towards the church building. So that he can finally be set free.
He enters into the SCOAN auditorium, and asisted by his wife.
He walkes back to his position by the altar.
and places the item on the floor, before the altar.
Next, he spreads out a filthy cloth on the floor
before bring each of the charms out of their containers
Mr Maku brings out many dirty charms, and objects including a grimy little padlock.
This is the pigeon and white pot the man of God had prophesied about last Sunday
This is the special bucket and sponge used in the ritual.
He brings out the wash bowl and sponge
At where we are, remain quiet, as we are about to listen to him.
explain !
The harms he has done to people with his charms.
and what the charms have caused in the lives of people.
We are seeing what is diplayed on the floor.
My name is Segu Maku. I worked in Benin as a transporter.
My father sent for me to come and meet him; he was a strong herbalist.
My father handed over all these charms and herbalist items to me.
saying that I should take over the work of a herbalist.
So, he gave everything to me.
I went to Edo State to start practising how to make charms.
People come to ask me to prepare charms for them.
When they come to me, I will tell them to write their opponent's name.
They will write the name and the residential address of the person.
I would first use this soap that I prepared to bathe.
This is the white bowl the man of God prophesied about last Sunday service.
It's very powerful.
This is the white bowl the man of God prophesied about during last Sunday service.
That Mr. Maku had left at home because he was afraid to touch it.
How do the soap and pigeon work together ?
Tell us the work.
I prepared the soap, if I want to use the soap with the pigeon.
I will use the soap to bathe with my special sponge and bucket.
This is the bucket.
After bathing with the special soa[, sponge and bucket,
I would put the name that was given to me in the pigeon's claws or mouth.
I would then command the pigeon to do the job and come back.
And then, the pigeon will fly to the address that was put in its claws
The pigeon would drop the paper on the roof of the person, then come back.
Before daybreak, the job would be done.
He mentioned earlier, the soap and pigeon work together.
He said that the first thing that he would do is to bathe with the soap in the white bowl.
Then he will go to the pigeon to command it to go and destroy.
If any customer came to him, saying that he wanted to hurt someone.
Mr. Segu Maku would ask them to write the person's name and address.
and what they wanted to happen to the person in question.
Then, he would put the paper in the pigeon's beak or claws and commanded it to go and complete the task.
He added that the pigeon would immediately fly to the roof of the person's house.
and drop the paper on their roof.
By morning, whatever the customer had requested would have happened.
Then the pigeon would fly back to him, to report his success speaking with a human voice, only he could hear.
What are the kinds of the jobs you normally send the pigeon to do ?
I used to send it to cause someone to have a stroke.
It can cause somebody to have a stroke, It does as I command.
I can send it to London or anywhere; it will return and give me the feedback.
I can cause someone to have a mental illness.
Or whatever the costomer requests.
Mr. Maku said that the pigeon could be used to make someone to have a mental disorder.
To cause stroke, to maim or to do any evil thing that he wanted to happen.
All he had to do was to command the pigeon, and it would carry out his order.
Mr. Segu Maku then said, that the pigeon could go anywhere, to any country, all across the world.
If any woman wants a husband or wants to collect money from the man's hands.
Firstly, I would tell the woman to get a bitter kola, swallow it and excrete it.
I would look for a special rope that we use for this job and take the bitter kola.
I would ask the woman for some of her pubic hair, finger nails, hair from...
her armpits and a native pot.
I would prepare the concoction. I would ask the woman
what she wants to happen to the person.
If she puts it in his food or soft drink and the man eats it or drink it.
whatever she has asked for would be done for her.
It is a command and so it shall remain in the life of the person forever.
I can send the pigeon to any country - Nigeria or even London.
Have you sent the pigeon to London before ?
I sent this to ....uh
He has sent the pigeon to London before.
He sent it out to London !
The wife is confirming it.
I have sent this pigeon to Italy.
One woman gave me the job that her husband disappointed her,
So, I sent the pigeon there to do the job.
He had sent the pigeon to London and Italy in the past.
There was one particular woman, who said that the man had disappointed her, and she wanted him to be destroyed.
Mr. Segu Maku send the pigeon to Italy, and the man was indeed destroyed.
Whenever I send the pigeon to do a bad job, when it comes back,
it would talk to me physically. Nobody else would know what the pigeon is saying.
I can also send the pigeon to cause an accident.
What is it again ? There is no destruction the pigeon cannot do.
You have to accept Jesus as your Lord and Saviour.
I am ready to accept Jesus Christ today as my Saviour.
Do you have people that you have chained or tied down with this charm ?
Many people, sir.
I have much work at hand that people have already paid me to do, but
I will drop it now because I want to give my life to Christ.
The man of God asked Mr Segu Maku if he had tied any one down by his charms and practices ?
To which he answered yes, "Many are tied down till this moment".
And he has collected money from several people to do other jobs for them.
But, he has abandon all of them, because he wants to give his life to Christ.
You have any question any where ?
The woman please come....
Emmanuel !
My name is Florence Alumona.
Dose he kill people that have Jesus - a born-again Christian ?
Clap for her !
The woman was asking you what about a born again Christian ?
With the born-again Christians, it's quite different. Some people go to church.
but also patronise herbalists
But if it is a true Christian, the pigeon will come back and
say that it does not have the power to kill the born again Christian.
This is why we ask the question.
Those of you that go to church and still go to witch doctor,
if they don't catch you !
The belief of many is that the pigwon needs to be burnt.
If you burn the pigeon, the demon in it will go out but you only burn its flesh.
The answer is deliverance and let the pigeon continue to live.
He will be delivered and the wife also will be delivered.
You said there is a man that comes to you physically. With which vehicle ?
A white Mercedes Benz and he appears wearing dreadlocks.
The man looks like a human being but he is a ghost.
He came to me and said that he needs my blood.
You cannot estimate the number of people you have destroyed.
I cannot count how many people.
because anybody would pay, I would do the job.
I have been doing it for 20 years.
I will deliver you and I will deliver the pigeon at the same time.
I don't need to go and touch it.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ !
Holy Ghost Fire !
The power of the Holy Spirit blew Mr Segu Maku off his feet.
Now under the sanctifying influence of the Holy Spirit, he is been disconnected
from every chain satan had used to connect him to himself.
They are receiving deliverance in the name of Jesus Christ.
Both Mr Maku and his pigeon.
Thank you Lord, they are free.
Glory be to God !
You are seeing the pigeon !
The name Jesus brings light where there is darkness.
The name Jesus brings understanding where there is ignorance.
The name Jesus brings awareness of righteousness where there is sin.
The name Jesus brings joy where there is sadness.
above all !
Contentment !
Give him the mic let him call the name of Jesus, see what would happen to him ?
Jesus
See what is happening to him ?
By calling the name Jesus Christ, you can see him shaking, right now ...
Down he goes !
That is one of his children crying !
If you agree with me that Jesus is greater than your knees, let me see your hand.
This padlock is used when he'd mention people's name and lock it.
We are going to loosen the padlock now so the people can be free.
1200 people's names
I will personally open it myself.
1200 people have just been unlocked,
from the bondage they have been feeling for years.
The man of God directed by the Spirit of God, unlocked the evil that this witch doctor has done
with this padlock that we are seeing right there.
The man of God directed by the Spirit of God just released 1200 people who were locked in bondage.
Man of God, what you said about the padlock is true.
My husband used it to lock people's destinies - thousands of people
A lot of people are getting free now.
But they don't know how the freedom came.
Come !
Who is a new comer here ?
In the name of Jesus, just speak ! To her. See what happen ?
The man is a new comer, he has been called out among the new comers to go forward...
He will use the mighty power in the name of Jesus.
In the name of Jesus.
Down she goes !
In the mighty power of the name of Jesus.
I am very surprised, and surprise again. I am very happy.
The need for you to live for God.
Stop sinning.
The name Jesus brings light where there is darkness.
The name Jesus brings understanding where there is ignorance.
The name Jesus brings awareness of righteousness where there is sin.
The name Jesus brings joy where there is sadness.
Above all..
Contentment !
Testimony Time
After Mr Maku's deliverance, he is presented with cash gift of N300.000.
And a Holy Bible.
To further asist Mr Maku and his family as a platform to start a business.
So that he won't go back to his former way of life to make ends meet.
My name is Segun Maku.
This woman is my wife. There are my sons and my daughters.
The moment I came to The SCOAN, I knew that God is existing here.
to make my life change from worst to good.
I thank God for my life today.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ !
Holy Ghost Fire !
The power of the Holy Spirit blew Mr Maku off his feet.
Now under the sanctifying influence of the Holy Spirit, he is been disconnected
from every chain satan had used to connect him to himself.
That really delivered me.
The monent I was delivered, something came out of my body.
That was the evil power of the charm.
Let him call the name of Jesus, see what will happen to him.
Jesus !
See what is happening to him ?
By calling the name of Jesus Christ, you can see him shaking uncontrollably.
Down he goes !
Jesus is very great ! Now, I am a free man.
I don't see anything anymore.
If I sleep at night now, I sleep like a young man,
I am a free man ; my body is very free.
Let him call the name of Jesus, see what will happen to him ?
Jesus !
See what is happening to him ?
By calling the name of Jesus Christ, you can see him shaking uncontrollably.
Down he goes !
Now I have given my life to Christ, I want Christ to take control of my life.
After Mr Maku's deliverance, he is presented with cash gift of N300.000, and a Holy Bible.
To further asist Mr Maku and his family as a platform to start a business.
So that he won't go back to his former way of life to make ends meet.
God is alive.
Prophet T.B. Joshua gave me the sum of N300.000 and a Holy Bible.
The Bible is very great in my life now. I will be reading it all the time.
Both in the mornign when I wake up and in the evening when I go to sleep. On Sunday, I will come to the service.
I want to follow God in a true way.
To God be the glory, we thank God almighty !
You have decided to give your life to Jesus Christ.
Having experienced a lot, the Lord is the only way.
We thank God almighty, today you are presented with the sum of N300.000
And four bags of rice - I am very grateful because I did not expect this.
I only came here for deliverance, but this great gift - I really value it.
When I go back home, I will use this food to feed my family.
and this money to start a business.
We thank God almighty for your life,
and we pray that the Lord will grant you the grace to maintain your deliverance.
Also live your life for our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ in Jesus name.
Amen
Let's hear from your wife, we believe she has one or two things to contribute
to the wonderful deliverance you receive today.
Madam, we thank God almighty for your life. Tell us your name.
My name is Caroline Maku.
I really thank God for the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
God used Prophet T.B. Joshua to deliver my husband from the hands of satan.
I so much thank God.
Assuming he did not come here to submit all those things (charms).
I didn't know about the whole story until now.
I know that God is here.
Before, my husband did not even know God.
I was surprised because we came here for deliverance.
Since then, the man of God has been taking care of me and my family.
He gave us money because he said that he does not want us,
to live off money from the charm any more.
I was amazed because Prophet T.B. Joshua gave my husband N300.000.
He also gave my children scholarships and gave us a Holy Bible.
He also gave us four bags of rice.
In fact, I will tell the whole world that there is Spirit of God in this church.
Thank you very much. We thank God almighty for what God has done in your life,
and for the life of your husband of bring the family together.
Also for taking the kingdom of darkness off of you.
To the glory of God.
I want to use this opportunity to inform you and your husband.
It's not enough to come to Jesus Christ for deliverance.
God almighty is in all ages, gethering into himself during speech of the worshippers
We also have a role to play !
The Bible says we should worship God in spirit and in truth.
I will also pray that the new found love in Christ Jesus,
new found life in Christ Jesus will remain permanent.
As he maintains his special relationship with our Savior Jesus Christ, in Jesus name.
Amen.
Thank you very much !
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today.
and stay up-to-date for the latest prophecies, deliverances, service and testimonies from the SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV, changing lives, changing nations, and changing the world.